So I'm a city planner, an urban designer,
我是一名城市规划师和设计师
former arts advocate,
曾经的艺术倡导者
trained in architecture and art history,
学过建筑设计和艺术史
and I want to talk to you today not about design
但是我今天想聊的跟设计无关
but about America
我要跟大家聊聊美国
and how America can be more economically resilient,
关于美国经济如何能够更加富有弹性
how America can be healthier,
如何更健康
and how America can be
以及美国怎样可以
more environmentally sustainable.
保持环境的可持续性
And I realize this is a global forum,
我知道这是一个全球性的论坛
but I think I need to talk about America
不过我觉得我需要说一说美国
because there is a history,
因为在历史上
in some places, not all,
在某些地方
of American ideas being appropriated,
美国的经验常被借鉴
being emulated, for better or for worse,
被模仿，结果有好有坏
around the world.
（这样的例子）全球都有
And the worst idea we've ever had
我知道的其中最坏的一个
is suburban sprawl.
便是郊区蔓延 (suburban sprawl) (译注:对于郊区范围没有止境大幅度扩张的现象)
It's being emulated in many places as we speak.
它被很多地区借鉴和模仿
By suburban sprawl, I refer to the reorganization
郊区蔓延，我指的是对景观道路建筑
of the landscape and the creation of the landscape
进行重新规划和建设
around the requirement of automobile use,
以满足汽车使用的需要
and that the automobile that was once an instrument of freedom
汽车曾经是象征自由的工具
has become a gas-belching,
如今成了排放废气
time-wasting and life-threatening
浪费时间和威胁生命的
prosthetic device
假肢设备
that many of us need just to,
我们很多人依赖汽车
most Americans, in fact, need,
大多数美国人依赖汽车
just to live their daily lives.
仅是为了他们的日常生活而已
And there's an alternative.
汽车其实并非不可替代
You know, we say, half the world is living in cities.
全世界有一半人在城市中生活
Well, in America, that living in cities,
在美国，许多人
for many of them, they're living in cities still
在城市里生活，却同样的
where they're dependent on that automobile.
依赖他们的汽车
And what I work for, and to do,
而我的工作目标
is to make our cities more walkable.
就是使城市变得适宜步行
But I can't give design arguments for that
但是我个人并没有
that will have as much impact
特别的设计主张
as the arguments that I've learned
我只是学习了
from the economists, the epidemiologists
来自于经济学家，流行病学家
and the environmentalists.
和环境学家的设计方案
So these are the three arguments that I'm going
今天天我将会阐述
to give you quickly today.
三个不同的设计论点
When I was growing up in the '70s,
我生长于70年代
the typical American spent one tenth of their income,
那时人们一般会把十分之一的收入
American family, on transportation.
花在交通上
Since then, we've doubled the number of roads
从那时起，我们的公路数量翻了一倍
in America, and we now spend one fifth
而我们现在要把五分之一的收入
of our income on transportation.
花在在交通上
Working families, which are defined as
劳动家庭，这里是指
earning between 20,000 and 50,000 dollars
年收入在两万至五万美元的
a year in America
美国家庭
are spending more now on transportation
花在交通上的开支
than on housing, slightly more,
甚至略微多于住房开销
because of this phenomenon called "drive till you qualify,"
这种现象被称为 “一直把车开到能买得起房的郊区”
finding homes further and further and further
家被安置在离市中心和工作
from the city centers and from their jobs,
越来越远的地方
so that they're locked in this, two, three hours,
他们陷在了每天两个，三个
four hours a day of commuting.
甚至四个小时的通勤上
And these are the neighborhoods, for example,
例如，在加州的中央山谷中
in the Central Valley of California
有这么一些社区
that weren't hurt when the housing bubble burst
在房产泡沫破碎和汽油价格上涨的冲击下
and when the price of gas went up;
不仅仅是规模减小
they were decimated.
而是彻底消亡了
And in fact, these are many
事实上，你可以看到
of the half-vacant communities that you see today.
有很多入住率不足一半的社区
Imagine putting everything you have into your mortgage,
想象一下你用所有的家当和贷款买了房
it goes underwater, and you have to pay
房价不断缩水，你却要花
twice as much for all the driving that you're doing.
是现在两倍的时间在开车上
So we know what it's done to our society
现在我们知道了这对于社会的影响
and all the extra work we have to do
以及我们为了使用自己的汽车
to support our cars.
需要花费的额外的代价.
What happens when a city decides
如果一个城市将发展的重心, 从汽车上
it's going to set other priorities?
转移到别的地方会是什么样子?
And probably the best example we have here
俄勒冈州的波特兰可能是目前
in America is Portland, Oregon.
美国最好的一个例子
Portland made a bunch of decisions in the 1970s
波特兰在1970年代做了一系列决定
that began to distinguish it
这些决策逐渐地将这个城市
from almost every other American city.
同其他的美国城市区别开来
While most other cities were growing
当其他城市不断扩张
an undifferentiated spare tire of sprawl,
千篇一律地顺着轮胎印蔓延开来
they instituted an urban growth boundary.
他们制定了城市增长的边界
While most cities were reaming out their roads,
当大多数城市为了不断拓宽道路
removing parallel parking and trees
移走平行车位和行道树
in order to flow more traffic,
以增加车流量时
they instituted a skinny streets program.
他们却开始将机动车道变窄
And while most cities were investing in more roads
当大多数城市增加道路投资
and more highways, they actually invested
建设高速路时，他们投资在
in bicycling and in walking.
自行车路和人行道上
And they spent 60 million dollars on bike facilities,
他们在自行车设施上投入了六千万美元
which seems like a lot of money,
看起来是很多
but it was spent over about 30 years,
但这是30年的总和
so two million dollars a year -- not that much --
大约每年200万，其实并不多
and half the price of the one cloverleaf
只相当于他们决定要重建的
that they decided to rebuild in that city.
一条立交桥的开销的一半
These changes and others like them changed
这些变化改变了
the way that Portlanders live,
波特兰民众的生活方式
and their vehicle-miles traveled per day,
他们的驾车里程
the amount that each person drives,
平均到每个人
actually peaked in 1996,
在1996年达到峰值
has been dropping ever since,
从那以后便开始下降
and they now drive 20 percent less
同美国其他地区相比
than the rest of the country.
他们开车频率少20%
The typical Portland citizen drives
一个典型的波特兰市民
four miles less, and 11 minutes less per day
与以前相比，每天少开车4英里
than they did before.
或是11分钟
The economist Joe Cortright did the math
经济学家 Joe Cortright 计算过
and he found out that those four miles
发现这四英里
plus those 11 minutes
加上这11分钟
adds up to fully three and a half percent
加起来的总和约占
of all income earned in the region.
当地居民收入的3.5%
So if they're not spending that money on driving --
如果他们不把这些钱花在开车上
and by the way, 85 percent of the money
顺便说一下，花在开车上的钱
we spend on driving leaves the local economy --
只有15%会贡献给本地经济
if they're not spending that money on driving,
如果他们不把钱花在开车上
what are they spending it on?
他们会花在哪里呢？
Well, Portland is reputed to have
从人均占有量上看, 波特兰有很多第一
the most roof racks per capita,
人均拥有的车顶行李架是最多的,
the most independent bookstores per capita,
人均拥有的书店是最多的,
the most strip clubs per capita.
连脱衣舞俱乐部数量都是最多的.
These are all exaggerations, slight exaggerations
这些有一点点夸张, 或者夸大了
of a fundamental truth, which is Portlanders
但波特兰人的确
spend a lot more on recreation of all kinds
在各种娱乐活动上的花费
than the rest of America.
多于美国其他地区
Actually, Oregonians spend more on alcohol
事实上，俄勒冈人在酒精饮料上的消费
than most other states,
也比其他州来的多
which may be a good thing or a bad thing,
这可能是好事也可能是坏事
but it makes you glad they're driving less.
但是好在他们开车也比较少
(Laughter)
（笑声）
But actually, they're spending most of it in their homes,
实际上，他们将交通省下的钱大多花在了他们的家里
and home investment is about as local
家居开支是最能
an investment as you can get.
留在本地的消费
But there's a whole other Portland story,
还有另一个的波特兰故事
which isn't part of this calculus,
并不在预料之中
which is that young, educated people
那就是年轻的受过教育的人们
have been moving to Portland in droves,
纷纷涌入波特兰
so that between the last two censuses,
在过去两次人口普查之间
they had a 50-percent increase
受过大学教育的人
in college-educated millennials,
增加了50%
which is five times what you saw anywhere else
这是其他所有地方的5倍
in the country, or, I should say, of the national average.
或者说是全国平均数的5倍
So on the one hand, a city saves money for its residents
一方面，通过更适宜单车和步行的规划
by being more walkable and more bikeable,
一个城市可以帮其居民省钱
but on the other hand, it also is the cool kind of city
另一方面，这会使它成为一个很酷的
that people want to be in these days.
大家都喜欢搬来的城市
So the best economic strategy
所以最好的经济策略
you can have as a city
作为一个城市来说
is not the old way of trying to attract corporations
不是想方设法吸引大的公司
and trying to have a biotech cluster
努力拥有生物产业
or a medical cluster,
或是医疗产业
or an aerospace cluster,
又或是航天工业
but to become a place where people want to be.
而是变成一个大家喜欢生活的城市
And millennials, certainly, these engines of entrepreneurship,
有才华的年轻人，作为经济的发动机
64 percent of whom decide first
他们中的64%会先决定
where they want to live,
住在哪里
then they move there, then they look for a job,
然后搬过去，再找工作
they will come to your city.
他们会来到你的城市
The health argument is a scary one,
下一个关于健康的论点有一点吓人
and you've probably heard part of this argument before.
你可能已经听过其中的一部分
Again, back in the '70s, a lot's changed since then,
同样，回到70年代，很多已经发生改变
back in the '70s, one in 10 Americans was obese.
在70年代，10人中只有一人肥胖
Now one out of three Americans is obese,
现在3人中便有一人肥胖
and a second third of the population is overweight.
三分之二的人群超重
Twenty-five percent of young men
25%的年轻男性
and 40 percent of young women are too heavy
和40%的年轻女性因为体重过重
to enlist in our own military forces.
而达不到参军的要求
According to the Center for Disease Control,
根据疾病控制中心的数据
fully one third of all children born after 2000
三分之一的2000年后出生的孩子
will get diabetes.
将来会患上糖尿病
We have the first generation of children in America
这是美国第一次，这一代的孩子
who are predicted to live shorter lives than their parents.
预期寿命要短于他们的父母
I believe that this American healthcare crisis
我相信这次美国的健康危机
that we've all heard about
就如我们刚刚提到的
is an urban design crisis,
其实是一个城市规划的危机
and that the design of our cities lies at the cure.
可我们的城市设计却仍保持固有的模式
Because we've talked a long time about diet,
我们讨论了太多次饮食
and we know that diet impacts weight,
我们都知道饮食影响体重
and weight of course impacts health.
体重当然会影响健康
But we've only started talking about inactivity,
但我们才刚刚开始重视缺乏运动
and how inactivity born of our landscape,
我们的城市布局使我们生来缺乏运动
inactivity that comes from the fact that we live
缺乏运动的主因来自于我们生活在
in a place where there is no longer any such thing
一个缺少步行道路的城市
as a useful walk, is driving our weight up.
开车使我们越来越重
And we finally have the studies,
我们终于开始相关的研究
one in Britain called "Gluttony versus sloth"
一个英国的叫做“暴食与懒惰”的项目
that tracked weight against diet
通过观察体重对应饮食
and tracked weight against inactivity,
和体重对应运动的关系
and found a much higher, stronger correlation
发现了后者之间拥有
between the latter two.
更加紧密的关系
Dr. James Levine at, in this case,
James Levine医生在
the aptly-named Mayo Clinic
恰如其名的蛋黄酱诊所
put his test subjects in electronic underwear,
将测试仪器放置在电子内衣里
held their diet steady,
先保持稳定的饮食
and then started pumping the calories in.
然后开始增加卡路里的摄入
Some people gained weight,
有些人体重增加
some people didn't gain weight.
有些人体重没有增加
Expecting some metabolic or DNA factor at work,
考虑到一些新陈代谢或基因的影响
they were shocked to learn that the only difference
他们吃惊地发现
between the subjects that they could figure out
他们唯一能够发现的区别
was the amount they were moving,
便是他们运动的多少
and that in fact those who gained weight
事实上那些体重增加的人
were sitting, on average, two hours more per day
每天要比体重没有变化的人
than those who didn't.
多坐两个小时
So we have these studies that tie
这些研究把体重和
weight to inactivity, but even more,
缺乏运动联系起来
we now have studies that tie weight to where you live.
我们还有研究把体重和居住地联系了起来
Do you live in a more walkable city
你是否生活在一个适宜步行的城市？
or do you live in a less walkable city,
还是生活在一个不适宜步行的城市？
or where in your city do you live?
或者你生活在城市的哪个部分？
In San Diego, they used Walk Score --
在圣迭戈，他们有种步行指数
Walk Score rates every address in America
步行指数给每个美国地址
and soon the world
很快会给全世界的地址打分
in terms of how walkable it is --
取决于它有多么适宜步行
they used Walk Score to designate more walkable neighborhoods
他们通过步行指数指定适宜步行的社区
and less walkable neighborhoods.
和不适宜步行的社区
Well guess what? If you lived in a more walkable neighborhood,
猜猜发生了什么？如果你生活中适宜步行的社区
you were 35 percent likely to be overweight.
你会有35%的可能超重
If you lived in a less walkable neighborhood,
但如果你生活在不适宜步行的社区
you were 60 percent likely to be overweight.
你将会有60%的可能超重
So we have study after study now
我们有越来越多的研究
that's tying where you live
将你生活在哪里
to your health, particularly as in America,
同你的健康联系起来
the biggest health crisis we have is this one
我们拥有的最大的健康危机便是
that's stemming from environmental-induced inactivity.
如何阻止这种由环境诱导的缺乏运动的现象
And I learned a new word last week.
我上周学到了一个新词
They call these neighborhoods "obesageneric."
他们叫这种社区 “肥胖社区”
I may have that wrong, but you get the idea.
我可能拼写不准，但你知道是什么意思
Now that's one thing, of course.
现在，有一件事，当然
Briefly mentioning, we have an asthma epidemic
简短地被提到过，哮喘在这个国家
in this country.
逐渐流行
You probably haven't thought that much about it.
你可能没有想过太多
Fourteen Americans die each day from asthma,
每天有14个美国人死于哮喘
three times what it was in the '90s,
比90年代多了三倍
and it's almost all coming from car exhaust.
这几乎完全归结于汽车尾气的排放
American pollution does not come
美国的污染来源不再是工厂
from factories anymore, it comes from tailpipes,
而是来自于汽车的排气管
and the amount that people are driving in your city,
你的城市中开车的人数
your urban VMT, is a good prediction
以及车辆行驶里程能够很好的
of the asthma problems in your city.
推测你的城市的哮喘问题
And then finally, in terms of driving,
最后一点, 由于汽车驾驶问题
there's the issue of the single-largest killer
引发的车祸, 已经成为(美国)健康成人的
of healthy adults, and one of the largest killers
最大死亡威胁, 同时也是(美国)公民
of all people, is car crashes.
最大的死亡威胁之一.
And we take car crashes for granted.
我们认为车祸是不可避免的
We figure it's a natural risk
把它当做开车在路上的
of being on the road.
天然风险
But in fact, here in America, 12 people
事实上，在美国，每10万人中
out of every 100,000
每年有12个人
die every year from car crashes.
死于汽车事故
We're pretty safe here.
我们还是很安全的
Well, guess what? In England, it's seven per 100,000.
可是在英格兰，十万人中只有7人
It's Japan, it's four per 100,000.
在日本，十万人中只有4人
Do you know where it's three per 100,000?
你知不知道哪里是十万人中只有3人？
New York City.
纽约市
San Francisco, the same thing. Portland, the same thing.
旧金山，一样，波特兰，也一样
Oh, so cities make us safer
所以城市更加安全
because we're driving less?
因为我们更少开车？
Tulsa: 14 per 100,000.
萨尔塔：十万人中有14人
Orlando: 20 per 100,000.
奥兰多：十万人中有20人
It's not whether you're in the city or not,
这并非取决于你是不是在城市中
it's how is your city designed?
而是你的城市是如何设计的
Was it designed around cars or around people?
它是围绕车还是人来设计的？
Because if your city is designed around cars,
因为你的城市是围绕车来设计的
it's really good at smashing them into each other.
那么它会很擅长于使汽车撞在一起
That's part of a much larger health argument.
这属于健康论点的一部分
Finally, the environmental argument is fascinating,
最后，这个环境论点相当有趣
because the environmentalists turned on a dime
因为环境学家们大约在10年之前
about 10 years ago.
做了个急转弯
The environmental movement in America
美国的环保运动
has historically been an anti-city movement
历史性地被作为反城市运动
from Jefferson on.
从杰弗森开始
"Cities are pestilential to the health,
“城市是人类健康，
to the liberties, to the morals of man.
自由和道德的瘟疫。
If we continue to pile upon ourselves in cities,
如果我们继续将自己同欧洲那样
as they do in Europe, we shall become as corrupt
堆积在城市里，那么我们也会变得
as they are in Europe
如同欧洲那样堕落
and take to eating one another as they do there."
如同他们那样吃掉彼此。”
He apparently had a sense of humor.
他很明显有一些幽默
And then the American environmental movement
美国的环保运动
has been a classically Arcadian movement.
成为了经典的田园运动
To become more environmental, we move into the country,
为了变得更环保，我们搬到了乡村
we commune with nature, we build suburbs.
我们同大自然交流，我们建设了郊区
But, of course, we've seen what that does.
但是，我们看到了这些的结果
The carbon mapping of America,
美国的二氧化碳
where is the CO2 being emitted,
排放的地图
for many years only
很多年来
hammered this argument in more strongly.
强烈敲打着这一论点
If you look at any carbon map, because we map it per square mile,
如果你看着碳排放地图，因为我们用平方英里作为单位
any carbon map of the U.S.,
任何一张美国碳排放地图
it looks like a night sky satellite photo of the U.S.,
看起来都像是美国的夜间卫星图
hottest in the cities, cooler in the suburbs,
城市里最多，郊区少一些
dark, peaceful in the countryside.
还有完全干净的乡村
Until some economists said, you know,
直到一些环境学家指出
is that the right way to measure CO2?
这种测量二氧化碳的正确方式吗？
There are only so many people in this country at any given time,
在一个时间段里一个国家的人口数量是一定的
and we can choose to live where perhaps
我们可能可以选择生活在
we would have a lighter impact.
我们对环境影响更小的地区
And they said, let's measure CO2 per household,
然后他们说，让我们来测量每家的碳排放量
and when they did that, the maps just flipped,
当他们这么做的之后，碳排放地图彻底反了过来
coolest in the center city, warmer in the suburbs,
市区最少，郊区更多
and red hot in these exurban
乡村那些
"drive till you qualify" neighborhoods.
“一直把车开到能买得起房的郊区”的社区排放最多
So a fundamental shift, and now you have
所以这是一个根本的转变，我们现在有
environmentalists and economists like Ed Glaeser
Ed Glaeser这样的环境学家和经济学家
saying we are a destructive species.
说我们是破坏性的物种
If you love nature, the best thing you can do
如果你热爱自然，你最应该做的是
is stay the heck away from it,
离它远些
move to a city, and the denser the better,
搬到城市，越密集越好
and the denser cities like Manhattan
像曼哈顿这种约密集的城市
are the cities that perform the best.
会表现越好
So the average Manhattanite is consuming gasoline
曼哈顿的人均汽油消耗量之少
at the rate the rest of the nation hasn't seen since the '20s,
在其他地区20年代以后便再也没有见到过
consuming half of the electricity of Dallas.
人均电力消耗仅是达拉斯的一半
But of course, we can do better.
但是当然，我们可以做的更好
Canadian cities, they consume half the gasoline of American cities.
加拿大城市的人均汽油消耗是美国城市的一半
European cities consume half as much again.
欧洲城市消耗的是这一半的一半
So obviously, we can do better,
所以很明显，我们可以做到更好
and we want to do better, and we're all trying to be green.
我们想做的更好，我们努力生活得更加绿色
My final argument in this topic is that
我最后一个论点是
I think we're trying to be green the wrong way,
我们通往绿色的路走错了
and I'm one of many people who believes that
我是这类人其中的一个
this focus on gadgets,
迷恋一些机械小玩意儿
on accessorizing --
喜欢各种装饰品
What can I add to my house,
我可以给我的房屋加装什么
what can I add to what I've already got
我可以在我现有的装备加些什么
to make my lifestyle more sustainable? --
以使我的生活方式更加绿色环保?
has kind of dominated the discussion.
这些占据了几乎所有的讨论
So I'm not immune to this.
所以我也不能对此免疫
My wife and I built a new house
我太太和我在华盛顿的废弃土地上
on an abandoned lot in Washington, D.C.,
建造了一栋新房子
and we did our best to clear the shelves
我们尽可能地买下了环保店
of the sustainability store.
所有的东西
We've got the solar photovoltaic system,
我们买了太阳能电池系统
solar hot water heater, dual-flush toilets,
太阳能热水器，双冲水马桶
bamboo floors.
竹地板
A log burning in my German high-tech stove
燃烧木头的德国高科技火炉
apparently, supposedly, contributes less carbon
相对于丢弃在森林任其自我降解
to the atmosphere than were it left alone
应该能够减少对大气的
to decompose in the forest.
碳排放
Yet all of these innovations --
所有这些创意
That's what they said in the brochure.
都被他们写在宣传手册里
(Laughter)
（笑声）
All of these innovations together
但所有这些创意加起来
contribute a fraction of what we contribute
对环境的贡献是非常微小的
by living in a walkable neighborhood
同生活在三个路口便能到达
three blocks from a metro in the heart of a city.
通往市中心的地铁站的社区内相比
We've changed all our light bulbs to energy-savers,
我们把所有的灯泡换成了节能型
and you should do the same thing,
你也同样应该这么做
but changing all your light bulbs to energy-savers
但换掉所有的灯泡
saves as much energy in a year
一年所节省的能源
as moving to a walkable city does in a week.
只相当于搬进步行社区一周的效果
And we don't want to have this argument.
但我们并不想宣传这样的论点
Politicians and marketers are afraid
政治家和商人害怕
of marketing green as a "lifestyle choice."
把绿色作为”生活方式之选“来宣传
You don't want to tell Americans, God forbid,
他们不想告诉美国人，上帝保佑
that they have to change their lifestyle.
你们必须改变生活方式
But what if lifestyle was really about quality of life
但如果生活方式真的是生活质量的体现
and about perhaps something that we would all enjoy more,
可能有一些东西我们会更加喜欢
something that would be better than what we have right now?
一些东西比我们现有的更好
Well, the gold standard of quality of life rankings,
生活质量排名的黄金标准
it's called the Mercer Survey.
被称作美世调查
You may have heard of it.
你可能已经听说过
They rank hundreds of nations worldwide
他们给全世界数百个国家排名
according to 10 criteria that they believe add up
对他们认为跟生活质量相关的十个要素
to quality of life: health, economics, education,
进行评比：健康，经济，教育
housing, you name it.
住房, 等等
There's six more. Short talk.
还有其他六个，但来不及说了
(Laughter)
（笑声）
And it's very interesting to see that
非常有趣的是
the highest-ranking American city, Honolulu,
排名最高的美国城市是火奴鲁鲁
number 28, is followed by kind of the usual suspects
排在了28位，跟着的是预料中的
of Seattle and Boston and all walkable cities.
西雅图，波士顿等所有适宜步行的城市
The driving cities in the Sun Belt,
阳光地带的驾车城市
the Dallases and the Phoenixes and, sorry, Atlanta,
达拉斯，凤凰城和亚特兰大
these cities are not appearing on the list.
并没有出现在名单之中
But who's doing even better?
那谁做得更好？
The Canadian cities like Vancouver,
加拿大城市比如温哥华
where again, they're burning half the fuel.
再说一遍，他们只消耗我们一半的燃料
And then it's usually won by cities where they speak German,
还有说德语的城市通常表现不错
like Dusseldorf or Vienna,
像是杜塞尔多夫或维也纳
where they're burning, again, half as much fuel.
他们同样消耗我们一半的燃料
And you see this alignment, this strange alignment.
你看看这些排序，这些奇怪的排序
Is being more sustainble
都是关于环境的可持续性的
what gives you a higher quality of life?
什么能够给你更高的生活质量？
I would argue the same thing
我会说是那些能让你
that makes you more sustainble
可持续发展的东西
is what gives you a higher quality of life,
可以给你更高的生活质量
and that's living in a walkable neighborhood.
那就是生活在适宜步行的社区里
So sustainability, which includes our wealth
可持续发展，包含了我们的财富
and our health
和我们的健康
may not be a direct function of our sustainability.
可能不是一道直接的函数
But particularly here in America,
但尤其是在美国
we are polluting so much
我们制造了太多污染
because we're throwing away our time
因为我们把我们的时间，金钱
and our money and our lives on the highway,
和生活浪费在高速路上
then these two problems would seem to share
这两个问题有一个共同的解决方法
the same solution, which is to make our cities
那就是使我们的城市
more walkable.
更加适宜步行
Doing so isn't easy, but it can be done,
这并不容易，但一定可行
it has been done,
也曾经被实现过
and it's being done now in more than a few cities,
在世界上和我们国家的
around the globe and in our country.
多个城市实现过
I take some solace from Winston Churchill,
我想从丘吉尔得到一些安慰
who put it this way:
他这么说
"The Americans can be counted on
美国人可以被指望
to do the right thing
做正确的事情
once they have exhausted the alternatives." (Laughter)
但是仅当他们别无他法时.(笑声)
Thank you.
谢谢
(Applause)
（鼓掌）